

# **Axel Alavedra**

Programmer

# About

#### Phone:

+34 667 75 75 18

#### Email:

axel.alavedra@gmail.com

#### Portfolio:

axelalavedra.com

#### Linkedin:

Axel Alavedra Cabello

#### Address:

Terrassa, Barcelona, Spain

#### Languages

English: High
Spanish: Native
Catalan: Native

#### **Profile**

Programmer with over four years of experience in the video game industry and shipped PC/Console titles.

My areas of expertise are Gameplay and AI, with excellent software design and debugging skills.

Great passion for making games and working together with design teams.

#### **Career Summary**

#### Sep 2023 - Present

#### Al Programmer at Melbot

- Unreal Engine, GAS
- Al Behaviors
- Al Combat Systems
- Al Decision Making & Tools
- Gameplay mechanics

#### Sep 2021 - Sep 2023

## **Gameplay Programmer at**

#### **Melbot**

- Unity
- Development Tools
- Gameplay mechanics
- Al Behaviors
- Al Systems & Tools:
  - Behavior Tree Tool
  - Position Query System Tool
  - o Combat Circle System
  - Perception System

# July 2021 - Sep 2021

#### **Intern Programmer at Melbot**

- Unity
- Gameplay mechanics
- Al Behaviors
- Sole developer for PS4 port

## October 2016 - May 2017

## Intern Programmer at ViOD

#### **Games Studio**

- Player actions
- Al Behaviors
- · Gameplay mechanics
- Scoring system

#### **Professional Skills**

## **Programming:**

C++, C#

#### AI:

State Machine, Behavior Tree, Utility Al, Decision Making, Pathfinding

#### **Game Engines:**

Unity, Unreal Engine

#### **Development:**

Debugging, Profiling, Architecture Design

## **Shipped Titles**

- Nick Jr. Party Adventure -
  - October 2024
  - PC & Consoles
  - Unity
- My Little Pony: A Maretime Bay Adventure - May 2022
  - PC & Consoles
  - Unity

# **Educational Training**

## CITM (UPC)

# Bachelor's degree in Design and Development of Videogames

• Attended from Sept. 2017 to June 2021

#### **Escola PIA Balmes**

Certificate of Higher Education, Computer Games and Programming Skills

- Attended from Sept. 2015 to June 2017
- Unity Certified Programmer